...and hell followed with him.
Pale Rider is a western, drama film directed by Clint Eastwood.
A mysterious preacher protects a humble prospector village from a
greedy mining company trying to encroach on their land.
Preacher, played by Clint Eastwood.
Hull Barret, played by Michael Moriarty.
Sarah Wheeler, played by Carrie Snodgress.
Josh LaHood, played by Chris Penn.
Coy LaHood, played by Richard Dysart.
Megan Wheeler, played by Sydney Penny.
Pale Rider is a 1985 American Western film produced and directed by
Clint Eastwood, who also stars in the lead role.
The title is a reference to Death as one of the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse, described in a literary passage
(also spoken in the film's dialogue) as riding a pale horse; in the film, Eastwood rides a pale horse.
The film, which took in over $41 million at the box office,
became the highest-grossing Western of the 1980s.
It is Eastwood's only Western of the 1980s.
The film explores themes of gunslinger, showdown, blackmail, marshal, mine.
The tone is emotional.